[♪♪♪]
[Chief Loyalist] Report.
[Loyalist #1]
I believe I'm close.
I've been following a series
of exotic readings
that look promising.
[Chief Loyalist]
I will be the judge
of what is promising or not.
Keep me informed
of any data you uncover.
Report.
Nothing?
How about the rest of you?
Are you even trying?
Her return to glory
is in our hands!
Do you understand that?
We cannot fail!
The Weapon of Desolation
should be releasing
massive amounts of energy
during each creation event...
pulses so significant
they have to be traceable.
So trace them!
You're out there
making your little monsters,
and we will find you
so you can make them for us.
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ So much to see ♪
♪ Jump up, kick back
whip around and spin ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ Whip around and spin ♪
♪ For what's right ♪
[groaning]
[agent] What's this?
Your Mud Consumption
Supplemental Permit
has a smudge on the corner?
Hands on your head!
-[charging weapons]
What's going on?
Where am I?
[groaning] Uh... actually,
who am I?
Hey!
You people in suits,
you must be official
or something, right?
Sir, we are
from the Administration.
I can honestly tell you
we are literally as official
as it is possible to be.
Indeed, "official"
is our one defining trait.
[Jay] Uh, great.
Can you officially tell me
who I am?
[agent] Unlikely.
Our field database
only has files
on important people,
and, uh, well,
don't get your hopes up.
[scanner surging]
What?
Can that be right?
[scanner surging]
Agent Jay Walker.
Jay Walker, Jay Walker.
Jay Walker.
Hey, this guy's... management!
Oh, uh... thanks?
Sorry we didn't recognize you,
Agent Walker.
Can we get you
anything else, sir?
If this is a test,
I hope we passed, sir.
I'm up for a promotion
in a few decades,
so if you could put
in a good word for me--
Jay, it's you!
Agent Donovan!
Bro, I was so worried
when you didn't show up
for the inter-departmental
pickleball.
You... know me?
Know you?
Stop kidding around, Jay.
You're only
my best friend ever!
What are you doing
out here, buddy?
What's with these clothes?
Let's get you back
to your department.
[Jay] This is where I woke up.
First place
I ever remember being.
If coming here
doesn't unlock my memories,
I don't know what will.
All of us who flew
into the Merge
woke up in weird places,
but we all kept our memories.
Why are you the only one
with amnesia?
Maybe his brain
was less stable begin with?
-Come on, Jay.
-[Kai yelps]
Something here's
gotta trigger your brain.
Something!
Anything...
Frak, that's your dad?
Indeed!
Frak does have the honor
of being my offspring!
Sir Reginald Slitherbottom.
The pleasure is all yours.
And these
are my esteemed colleagues
in the Explorer's Club
of Ninjago!
Johnny Courageous!
Rowan Rockspike!
Seafoam Green!
Last, and also least, Gweeg.
Ha! Just pulling
your chain, Gweeg!
[grumbling]
Huh, your names
are all surprisingly stupid.
[all chuckling]
I like this one.
She's filled with vim!
[chuckling]
Good show!
[John] So, you're young Frak!
Your father has spoken of you!
Have I?
[laughing] Remember?
That one time we hired
that incompetent slug creature,
you jokingly referred
to him as "Frak."
[sighing]
Ah, yes, that I did, good sir.
Yeah, you do have
a rather impressive memory.
At times.
Introduce me
to your friends, son.
Oh, uh, Dad,
this is Sora,
Wyldfyre, and Riyu.
They're Ninja, just like me!
I'm a Ninja now!
[gasping] A Ninja?
You don't say!
How exciting,
but are there any real Ninja
here with you?
Dad, we're all real Ninja
and Elemental Masters. I--
Oh, yes, yes, yes,
of course you are,
but you do know what I mean.
The "classic" Ninja?
Who people
have actually heard of...
and like.
[grumbling]
The original Ninja
aren't with us right now,
but we do know all the Ninja,
and by the way, Master Lloyd,
the Legendary Green Ninja,
told me
I'm an excellent student.
I'm sure you're passable
as a student, son,
because you had
a brilliant teacher for a dad!
[Wyldfyre and Riyu growl]
Any chance you're heading
back to Ninjago?
We're in a bit of a hurry.
Well, if you need a lift,
there's plenty of room onboard
The Expanding Frontier...
that's the name of our airship,
and if we run out of room,
we'll just toss out Gweeg...
preferably from 2,000 feet up!
[all guffawing]
[grumbling]
Ah, just
pulling your chain, Gweeg!
Seriously, though,
we'd be happy to take you all
back to Ninjago.
Great!
As soon as our expedition
comes to a successful
conclusion!
What?
How long will that take?
The Explorer's Club
has come here to Umbrasylvis
following rumors
of a deadly monster
attacking the area.
The Club sent
its strongest members,
but they also sent Gweeg.
[all laughing]
[Gweeg grumbling]
Why do you keep
picking on that Gweeg guy?
Worry not!
Gweeg knows
it's all in good jest!
He likes it!
This is bonding!
-[grumbling]
So, you're here to protect
the town from a monster?
Well, that's one way
of putting it.
Our expedition is here
to capture the monster
so that we can bring it back
to Ninjago!
Why would you bring
a deadly monster
back to where you live?
To put it on display
and charge admission
as a Wonder
of the Merged Lands, of course!
That sounds dangerous.
No reason to be afraid,
little lady,
or my name
isn't Johnny Courageous!
Which it is!
I had it legally changed...
pending!
Dad, something's
seriously going wrong
with Elemental Powers.
We need to get back
to the Monastery
as soon as we can.
Undoubtedly!
And I'm sure the real Ninja
are eager
to see you again, Frak.
There are probably swords
that need polishing,
floors to sweep, and so forth.
Important Ninja work!
But in order
for the Explorer's Club
to return in glory,
we'll first need
to capture our prey.
Tonight, we hunt monsters!
[together] Huzzah!
Why don't you come along, son?
Even a mediocre student
such as yourself
might, uh. learn something.
Uh...
[sighing]
Sub-Agent Prentis,
shift's over.
What are you doing
still working?
New Merge Refugees.
Figuring out
where to send them.
You know my policy,
"When in doubt you might be,
send 'em to the Land..."
"Of Lee," yes.
I do love obeying a good rhyme,
and there is a pair of them,
per protocol,
but are you sure
that's where they're from?
I'm sure it's all fine.
Probably.
Just keep records.
[portal whooshing]
[game music chimes]
Ugh, thought he'd never leave.
I know, right?
Making us miss out
on valuable gaming time.
You gonna ask out
that cute Merlopian girl in HR?
She's totally
head over gills for you.
Uh, she's nice,
but I don't wanna date anybody.
I can't explain it.
It's like the perfect person
is already out there somewhere.
Out there?
[Jay] Yeah, look,
even though HR has shown me
my employee records,
and I've worked here
my whole life,
since I still
don't remember anything,
sometimes I feel like...
Feel like what?
You know,
I just found this picture
from our first
permit inspection.
The applicant tried to claim
a P-3 exemption on a CE-5!
Ha, ha, ha!
Sorry you don't
remember it, buddy,
but trust me,
we've had the best of times.
Yeah.
I guess we really did.
And still undefeated
Galamorph champ, Jay Walker!
[clanking]
That doesn't sound
natural to me.
[clanking]
Looks like someone
dug something up.
Or buried something.
[rocks tumbling]
That's the kind of suitcase
Administration Agents use.
[Kai gasps]
Your old gi.
This makes zero sense.
How could this be here?
"Request to bury
incriminating evidence.
Stamped and approved."
What does this mean?
It means the Administration
knew I was a Ninja.
They hid this here,
where I woke up with no memory.
We need to get there.
There's someone
I need to threaten
with intense violence!
I mean, have a discussion with.
[Reggie] Right!
Who's ready for a night
of monster hunting?
[Explorers] Huzzah!
Tonight we'll be using
these brand-new prototype
capture devices.
Behold!
Aah!
[grumbling]
Explorers!
Split up and find the monster!
[Explorers] Huzzah!
[Frak] Uh, is that a good idea?
There's safety in numbers.
Maybe you should go out
in groups of two or three?
Especially since
you don't know the area
and have no idea
what kind of monster
you're dealing with.
[Reggie chuckling]
My apologies, Explorers.
My naive son means well.
You forget, Frak,
the one who catches the monster
gets the all-important
naming rights, huh?
If we went in pairs,
who would get
to name the monster?
It'd be madness!
Oh, don't fret, son.
Yes, your idea was awful,
but I do like
that you tried to participate...
almost like
a little mini grown-up.
There's probably
no monster, right?
Monster or not,
these explorers
will probably get lost
or end up in a ditch somewhere.
We have to help.
Why? I don't help buffoons.
Personal policy.
[growling a question]
Why?
'Cause helping
is the Ninja way.
And one of them is my dad.
Yeah, still not convinced.
Okay, but if there's a chance
there really is a monster,
someone's gotta
protect this town.
[Wyldfyre sighs]
I guess it'd be cool
to fight a monster,
if there is one,
which I doubt.
[distant cat screeching,
dog barking]
Why do you let your dad
talk to you that way?
He's my dad.
Look, my parents
were a mess too.
Then you get it.
I haven't spoken to them
in years,
probably never will again.
Just 'cause someone's
related to you
doesn't mean
you have to take their abuse.
It's called
family loyalty, Sora.
Some of us obviously
have a harder time
just walking away from family
than you do.
Can't imagine the same trick
we used the last time
will work again.
Got a new plan
for getting in there?
Yeah, I got a guy.
Called him as soon as
I came up with the idea.
What guy?
Trust me, you'll love him.
[novelty horn honks
"La Cucaracha"]
[brakes screeching]
[coughing]
Jay!
My guy! [laughing]
Rapton!
[together] Rapton?
[grunting]
[chuckling]
Aw, Rapton's thrilled
to see you, you old outlaw!
It's been too long!
Jay hasn't seen you
since we pulled that job
in Shintaro!
[scoffing] Pfft!
Can you believe
some clown paid so much
for an ugly cursed skull?
[cackling]
[laughing] Don't make me laugh.
-Jay, you know this jerk?
-Jay, you know these jerks?
Oh, you've met?
We came when you called, Jay.
Whatcha need, brother?
Gotta get in there.
Jay's got a plan,
but Jay needs you
to help Jay pull it off.
How much will it cost?
For Jay?
Free of charge!
[grumbling]
Pow!
Yeah!
[♪♪♪]
Yeah! Whoo!
[fireworks blasting]
Cease!
You're breaking literally
15 different local ordinances!
[cackling]
We think ordinances are dumb!
It's cool to break 'em!
Yeah!
[tires squealing]
These hooligans and scofflaws
won't comply.
[firing blasters]
Move in!
[♪♪♪]
[whistling]
[body slumping]
Oh! Ow! Oh, no!
[engine roaring up]
Oh, why did we dare tangle
with the unstoppably dapper
Administration?
We must flee for our lives!
[stammering]
[engine roaring away]
Good work, Agents!
And the scofflaws
left a vehicle behind.
Have it confiscated!
[Nya] I can't believe
something Rapton did
actually worked!
[Kai] So where do we go now?
[Jay] He'll probably be
in his office soon.
[Nya] Who's "he"?
[Kai] I stopped
understanding anything
back when we were in a stomach.
[screeching]
[Wyldfyre] A real monster!
[monster hissing]
[panting]
[grunting with effort]
[Frak] Come on, work!
[ground rumbling]
[all yelping] Whoa!
[snarling]
[Sora gasps]
Don't let it get away!
[monster hissing overhead]
[yelping]
Courageous
might wanna change his name.
Ha ha!
[snarling]
[panting]
Work, powers, work!
Aah, fine, whatever!
H'yah!
[screaming]
[snarling]
Hmm. Hup!
Aah!
[Frak] Dad! No!
Oh, boy.
Oof!
[snarling]
[yelping]
[slamming]
[snarling]
[Riyu barks]
[barking]
[yelping]
[shrieking in pain]
[Riyu shrieks]
[Riyu groaning in pain]
[Sora] Come on,
powers, come on!
[Riyu shrieks]
[panting with effort]
[monster hissing]
[groaning in pain]
[both] Riyu!
Son, you tried to rescue me!
It's what I do, Dad--
But you only got in my way.
I would've trapped it myself
if you hadn't shown up.
Next time, think.
[Riyu groans]
[♪♪♪]
[snoring]
[light switch clicking]
[groaning] Lousy lights.
Now I have to
requisition repairs.
[chair wheels spinning]
Jay! Where have you been?
And what's with
the hair and uniform?
You went out on that
equipment reclamation operation
in Mysterium
and never came back.
Shut it, Blake!
I know it's an act.
My so-called best friend
with fake photos of us
as young agents together.
Fake?
What are you talking about?
I got receipts.
I wanted to believe
you weren't in on it...
maybe you had your memories
altered too,
but no!
A request to bury
incriminating evidence form,
and whose name
is on that signature line?
Tell me.
Agent Blake Donovan.
So you finally figured it out?
Took you long enough.
Who erased my memories?
Was it you?
Why? Tell me why!
You don't get it.
There are things
you'll never understand, Jay.
Is that so?
Well, one thing I do understand
is what this does.
You wouldn't.
You wanna bet?
Uh, what if, um...
What if I told you
how you could
unblock your memories.
[Jay] How?
33rd floor, Section A9.
Where your memories
were blocked.
There could be a way
to reverse it.
Why should I trust you?
Cause I'm the only hope
you have
of ever remembering
your real life.
Take me there.
No problem,
I'll just get you
the access code, and--
Chair! [clattering]
So long, suckers!
Ugh! That jerk-head!
[typing]
According to this,
the 33rd floor, Section A9
is the Department
of Vacation Simulation.
It's gotta be another lie.
Why would a Vacation department
have anything to do
with Jay's memory loss?
'Cause according to
what I'm seeing here,
they've got some
brain-accessing tech up there.
We can't stay here.
I'm sure Blake's
reported us already.
Agents will be on us in seconds.
-[banging]
-Freeze, enemies of bureaucracy!
Uh, I swear,
if this is another one
of Agent Donovan's pranks...
Aah!
[gasping]
I was afraid that'd happen.
I do not like elemental powers
being all messed up like this.
Thanks for the catch.
Any time.
We've been wandering for hours.
The dragon said I'd find
the Temple of the Green Ninja
if I was meant to.
[sighing]
Maybe I'm not meant to.
Maybe it's true,
I'm too old,
and it's too late
to do the Ritual.
Maybe you should try
meditating.
Who are you? Me?
It's what you'd
tell me to do, isn't it?
Should follow my own advice.
Get comfortable.
This might take a while.
[energy sparking]
I... feel something already.
Well, good thing
I didn't get comfortable.
Wait... this isn't
from my meditations.
It's...
[snarling]
Aah!
[grunting with effort]
[roaring]
We have captured
one of the Elemental Energy
creatures
formed by
the Weapon of Desolation.
[Chief Loyalist] You know
what you need to do, then...
and let no one
stand in your way.
[♪♪♪]